E: ankit.mahendru@gmail.com

W: www.ankitmahendru.com

Ankit Mahendru

Personal Statement

A passionate developer with several years of experience in web development complemented by a well-rounded knowledge of web frameworks. A keen eye for automation, performance optimization and data visualization. In addition, a proven track record of delivering successful projects and programs across a diverse range of technologies. Quick learner with the ability to support business partners and technology teams to provide successful deliveries. Excellent communication skills and global experience working with teams and stakeholders based in EMEA, Americas & Asia-Pacific.

Development Skills

- Advanced experience
 - o ASP.NET MVC & Web Forms (C#)
 - o Angular
 - o React
 - o JavaScript
 - o HTML, CSS & SCSS
 - o SQL
 - o GIT & TFS
- Intermediate experience
 - o TDD & unit tests via xUnit & NUnit
 - E2E and accessibility testing using protractor
 - o Storybook
 - o Ionic
 - o Dojo
 - o CI with TeamCity, Gitlab & Bitbucket
 - o Kubernetes

Soft Skills

- Stakeholder management using agile and waterfall methodologies
- Ability to evaluate and assess technical requirements as a scrum master
- Identify gaps, review and implement business improvements

Professional Experience

Senior Software Developer – N-able, Edinburgh, Scotland • Nov 2021 – present

- Develop and support Apple Device Management UI project
- Build components to enhance developer experience on in-house tools
- Review code or microservices that support Apple Device Management
- Integrate storybook and build component library
- Deployments via Azure and managed Kubernetes services

Senior Software Developer - Symplectic, Glasgow, Scotland • April 2019 - Oct 2021

- Develop and support Grant Tracker (Grant Management System)
- Extend Funding Solution API (ASP.NET Core API using MediatR and CQRS)
- Integrate UI/UX designs with stories in Storybook
- Development to extend Public Portal (AngularJS)
- Design new authentication components using TypeScript for React
- Modernizing an MVC application with multiple React features
- Schema related changes for an inhouse Entity Generator. A windows application that makes use of Subsonic ORM
- Web Accessibility using a11y
- Implement BEM CSS methodology
- Reduction in legacy code
- Reduce number of steps to enhance user journey

Software Developer - Ceridian, Glasgow, Scotland • Nov 2017 - April 2019

- Develop and support HR system
- Implement features such as Global Direct Deposit and Payzone Management
- Letter/Contract management for employees and candidates
- Develop and maintain the candidate portal
- Account recovery assistant
- Configure workflows for approval processes
- Reports Management (Build and alter reports using database entities)
- Enhance imports and exports (HR & Org)
- Generate tax forms using imagemagick and ghostscript
- Assist employees during TFS/GIT migration

Software Developer – Scottish Qualifications Authority, Glasgow, Scotland • June 2016 – July 2017

- Migrating IBM WebSphere applications (Java) and existing Ingres databases to Microsoft
 Net stack using EF6 Code first using MVC 5 & Microsoft SQL 2012.
- Building web services using SoapUI and Automapper.
- Configure web apps and setup continuous deployments with TeamCity to IIS server
- Oversee development work done by 3rd parties along with code reviews and user testing.
- Assisting in scoping efforts for new developments & transitions of existing technologies to new efficient models.

Application Developer –Spaarks, Glasgow, Scotland • July 2011 – June 2016

- Develop, support and optimize applications for Deutsche Bank network, Vivacity RTO
 Coaching & ACT Health. Worked closely with end users to provide front line support and
 improve performance dramatically within tight timescales.
- Develop and maintain pass office and UBR structural changes across various access control systems for Deutsche Bank CSBC Group.
- Incorporate integration to Deutsche Bank Visitor Management systems and Smartcard physical identification cards.
- Developed code and supported various banking applications that deal with onboarding of contractors and third party vendors in Germany and Singapore.
- Manage costs and policy compliance data from various sources across DB and provide standardized end user reporting by UBR, Cost Centre and region.
- Develop and support a fully auditable online process for external requests and resources.

- Gathered business requirements, designed solutions with support from technical specialists and managed workload across the team.
- Implement new workflows for disaster recovery reporting systems within the bank.
- Implement Restful web services to provide consistent HR data feeds within Deutsche Bank GTO group.
- Pull together a number of datasets from numerous sources into a single, central reporting solution.
- Implement rich interactive dashboards that demonstrate time spent against cost management policies and obligations for ACT Health in Australia.
- Develop cross platform mobile apps that help users manage and lend out medical training equipment to their members.
- Service desk management Service Now, Zendesk, Jira.

Education & Certifications

Masters of Science **Information Technology** – University of Glasgow, Glasgow Scotland • 2011 **Bachelor** of Science **Information Technology** – University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India • 2009

Administering Visual Studio Team Foundation Server 2012 - Exam ID: 070496 • May 2013 Windows Based Client Development (Microsoft .NET Framework 2.0) Exam ID: 526 • April 2010 Application Development Foundation (Microsoft .Net Framework 2.0) Exam ID: 536 • Nov 2009